{
	"questionList": [{
			"question": "What is difference between JDK,JRE and JVM? ",
			"answer": " JVM is an acronym for Java Virtual Machine, it is an abstract machine which provides the runtime environment in which java bytecode can be executed. It is a specification.\nJVMs are available for many hardware and software platforms (so JVM is platform dependent).\nJRE stands for Java Runtime Environment. It is the implementation of JVM.\nJDK is an acronym for Java Development Kit. It physically exists. It contains JRE + development tools.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " How many types of memory areas are allocated by JVM?",
			"answer": " Class(Method) Area\nHeap\nStack\nProgram Counter Register\nNative Method Stack",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is JIT compiler?",
			"answer": " Just-In-Time(JIT) compiler:It is used to improve the performance. JIT compiles parts of the byte code that have similar functionality at the same time, and hence reduces the amount of time needed for compilation.Here the term “compiler” refers to a translator from the instruction set of a Java virtual machine (JVM) to the instruction set of a specific CPU.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is platform? ",
			"answer": "A platform is basically the hardware or software environment in which a program runs. There are two types of platforms software-based and hardware-based. Java provides software-based platform. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the main difference between Java platform and other platforms?",
			"answer": "The Java platform differs from most other platforms in the sense that it's a software-based platform that runs on top of other hardware-based platforms.It has two components:\nRuntime Environment\nAPI(Application Programming Interface) ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What gives Java its 'write once and run anywhere' nature? ",
			"answer": " The bytecode. Java is compiled to be a byte code which is the intermediate language between source code and machine code. This byte code is not platform specific and hence can be fed to any platform.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is classloader? ",
			"answer": " The classloader is a subsystem of JVM that is used to load classes and interfaces.There are many types of classloaders e.g. Bootstrap classloader, Extension classloader, System classloader, Plugin classloader etc.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " If I don't provide any arguments on the command line, then the String array of Main method will be empty or null?",
			"answer": "It is empty. But not null. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What if I write static public void instead of public static void? ",
			"answer": " Program compiles and runs properly.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the default value of the local variables? ",
			"answer": " The local variables are not initialized to any default value, neither primitives nor object references.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the advantage of Properties file?",
			"answer": " If you change the value in properties file, you don't need to recompile the java class. So, it makes the application easy to manage.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "Why we override equals() method? ",
			"answer": " The equals method is used to check whether two objects are same or not. It needs to be overridden if we want to check the objects based on property.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " How to synchronize List, Set and Map elements?",
			"answer": "Yes, Collections class provides methods to make List, Set or Map elements as synchronized ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the advantage of generic collection? ",
			"answer": " If we use generic class, we don't need typecasting. It is typesafe and checked at compile time.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is hash-collision in Hashtable and how it is handled in Java?",
			"answer": " Two different keys with the same hash value is known as hash-collision. Two different entries will be kept in a single hash bucket to avoid the collision",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the Dictionary class?",
			"answer": " The Dictionary class provides the capability to store key-value pairs.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the default size of load factor in hashing based collection?",
			"answer": " The default size of load factor is 0.75. The default capacity is computed as initial capacity * load factor. For example, 16 * 0.75 = 12. So, 12 is the default capacity of Map.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is Exception Handling? ",
			"answer": "Exception Handling is a mechanism to handle runtime errors.It is mainly used to handle checked exceptions. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is difference between Checked Exception and Unchecked Exception?",
			"answer": " Checked Exception\nThe classes that extend Throwable class except RuntimeException and Error are known as checked exceptions e.g.IOException,SQLException etc. Checked exceptions are checked at compile-time.\nUnchecked Exception\nThe classes that extend RuntimeException are known as unchecked exceptions e.g. ArithmeticException,NullPointerException etc. Unchecked exceptions are not checked at compile-time.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the base class for Error and Exception? ",
			"answer": "Throwable. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "Is it necessary that each try block must be followed by a catch block? ",
			"answer": "It is not necessary that each try block must be followed by a catch block. It should be followed by either a catch block OR a finally block. And whatever exceptions are likely to be thrown should be declared in the throws clause of the method. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is finally block?",
			"answer": " finally block is a block that is always executed.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "Can finally block be used without catch? ",
			"answer": " Yes, by try block. finally must be followed by either try or catch.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " Is there any case when finally will not be executed?",
			"answer": "finally block will not be executed if program exits(either by calling System.exit() or by causing a fatal error that causes the process to abort). ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "Can an exception be rethrown? ",
			"answer": " yes",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "Can subclass overriding method declare an exception if parent class method doesn't throw an exception ? ",
			"answer": " Yes but only unchecked exception not checked.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is exception propagation ?",
			"answer": " Forwarding the exception object to the invoking method is known as exception propagation.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is Garbage Collection?",
			"answer": " Garbage collection is a process of reclaiming the runtime unused objects.It is performed for memory management.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is gc()? ",
			"answer": " gc() is a daemon thread.gc() method is defined in System class that is used to send request to JVM to perform garbage collection.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the purpose of finalize() method?",
			"answer": " finalize() method is invoked just before the object is garbage collected.It is used to perform cleanup processing.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " Can an unrefrenced objects be refrenced again?",
			"answer": " yes",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What kind of thread is the Garbage collector thread? ",
			"answer": " Daemon thread.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the purpose of the Runtime class? ",
			"answer": " The purpose of the Runtime class is to provide access to the Java runtime system.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " How will you invoke any external process in Java?",
			"answer": " By Runtime.getRuntime().exec(?) method",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is serialization?",
			"answer": "Serialization is a process of writing the state of an object into a byte stream.It is mainly used to travel object's state on the network ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is Deserialization?",
			"answer": " Deserialization is the process of reconstructing the object from the serialized state.It is the reverse operation of serialization.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is transient keyword? ",
			"answer": " If you define any data member as transient,it will not be serialized.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is Externalizable ",
			"answer": " Externalizable interface is used to write the state of an object into a byte stream in compressed format.It is not a marker interface.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between Serializalble and Externalizable interface?",
			"answer": " Serializable is a marker interface but Externalizable is not a marker interface.When you use Serializable interface, your class is serialized automatically by default. But you can override writeObject() and readObject() two methods to control more complex object serailization process. When you use Externalizable interface, you have a complete control over your class's serialization process. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between the Reader/Writer class hierarchy and the InputStream/OutputStream class hierarchy? ",
			"answer": " The Reader/Writer class hierarchy is character-oriented, and the InputStream/OutputStream class hierarchy is byte-oriented.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What an I/O filter?",
			"answer": " I/O filter is an object that reads from one stream and writes to another, usually altering the data in some way as it is passed from one stream to another. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " Can you access the private method from outside the class?",
			"answer": " Yes, by changing the runtime behaviour of a class if the class is not secured.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What are wrapper classes? ",
			"answer": "Wrapper classes are classes that allow primitive types to be accessed as objects. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is a native method?",
			"answer": " A native method is a method that is implemented in a language other than Java.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the purpose of the System class? ",
			"answer": "The purpose of the System class is to provide access to system resources. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What comes to mind when someone mentions a shallow copy in Java? ",
			"answer": " Object cloning.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is singleton class? ",
			"answer": " Singleton class means that any given time only one instance of the class is present, in one JVM.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " Which containers use a border layout as their default layout?",
			"answer": " The Window, Frame and Dialog classes use a border layout as their default layout.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " Which containers use a FlowLayout as their default layout?",
			"answer": " The Panel and Applet classes use the FlowLayout as their default layout.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are peerless components?",
			"answer": " The peerless components are called light weight components.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " Is the difference between a Scrollbar and a ScrollPane?",
			"answer": " A Scrollbar is a Component, but not a Container. A ScrollPane is a Container. A ScrollPane handles its own events and performs its own scrolling.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "coreJava"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is Android?",
			"answer": " Android is an open-source, Linux-based operating system used in mobiles, tablets, televisions, etc.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " Who is the founder of Android?",
			"answer": " Andy Rubin.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "Does android support other languages than java? ",
			"answer": " Yes, an android app can be developed in C/C++ also using android NDK (Native Development Kit). It makes the performance faster. It should be used with Android SDK.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is activity in Android?",
			"answer": "Activity is like a frame or window in java that represents GUI. It represents one screen of android. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "  What is intent?",
			"answer": " It is a kind of message or information that is passed to the components. It is used to launch an activity, display a web page, send SMS, send email, etc. There are Implicit Intent,Explicit Intent",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " what is Android toast?",
			"answer": " An android toast provides feedback to the users about the operation being performed by them. It displays the message regarding the status of operation initiated by the user. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "  Explain the use of 'bundle' in android?",
			"answer": "We use bundles to pass the required data to various subfolders. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is an application resource file?",
			"answer": " The files which can be injected for the building up of a process are called as application resource file. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is service in android? ",
			"answer": " A service is a component that runs in the background. It is used to play music, handle network transaction, etc. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is AAPT?",
			"answer": " AAPT is an acronym for android asset packaging tool. It handles the packaging process.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is a content provider? ",
			"answer": " A content provider is used to share information between Android applications.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is fragment?",
			"answer": "The fragment is a part of Activity by which we can display multiple screens on one activity. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is ADB? ",
			"answer": " ADB stands for Android Debug Bridge. It is a command line tool that is used to communicate with the emulator instance.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is NDK?",
			"answer": " NDK stands for Native Development Kit. By using NDK, you can develop a part of an app using native language such as C/C++ to boost the performance.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the Google Android SDK? ",
			"answer": " The Google Android SDK is a toolset which is used by developers to write apps on Android-enabled devices. It contains a graphical interface that emulates an Android-driven handheld environment and allows them to test and debug their codes.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is an APK format?",
			"answer": " APK is a short form stands for Android Packaging Key. It is a compressed key with classes, UI's, supportive assets and manifest. All files are compressed to a single file is called APK.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is a singleton class in Android? ",
			"answer": "A singleton class is a class which can create only an object that can be shared by all other classes. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What do you mean by a drawable folder in Android?",
			"answer": " In Android, a drawable folder is compiled a visual resource that can use as a background, banners, icons, splash screen, etc.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is sleep mode in Android?",
			"answer": " In sleep mode, CPU is slept and doesn't accept any commands from android device except Radio interface layer and alarm.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is nine-patch images tool in Android? ",
			"answer": "We can change bitmap images into nine sections with four corners, four edges, and an axis. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " Define and explain the Android Framework. ",
			"answer": " Android framework is a set of API’s using which the Android developers write code for the mobile apps. It contains the methods and classes to write the programming code.Android framework includes a different set of tools to create image pane, text field, buttons, etc. It also includes “Activities” with which the user interacts and “Services”, which are the programs that run in the background. It is a package of different components like Intents, Broadcast Receivers, Content Providers, etc.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "Explain Activity Lifecycle briefly. ",
			"answer": " When a user interacts with the app and moves here and there, out of the app, returns to the app, etc. During all this process (Activity) instances also move in the different stages in their lifecycle.There are seven different states  like –\n onCreate(), \nonStart(), \nonRestart(), \nonResume(), \nonPause(), \nonStop(), \nand onDestroy().\n These are termed as a ‘callback’. Android system invokes these callbacks to know that the state has been changed.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is AIDL? ",
			"answer": "In the Android platform, there are remote methods that facilitate the use of methods from one program to another. To create and implement the remote methods the first step is to define the communication interface in AIDL. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "android"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is C#?",
			"answer": "C# is a simple, modern, general purpose programming language. It is an object oriented programming language developed by Microsoft. It is a safe and managed language that is compiled by .NET framework to generate Microsoft intermediate language (machine code). ",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the reason behind the invention of C#?",
			"answer": " C# is designed for Common Language Infrastructure (CLI). It contains the executable code and runtime environment that makes the users able to use various high-level languages on different computer platforms and architectures.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the main reasons to use C# language?",
			"answer": " These are top reasons to use C# language:\nEasy to learn\nGeneral purpose and object oriented programming language\nComponent oriented\nStructured language\nCan be compiled on variety of computer platforms\nProduces efficient programs Part of .net framework",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between public, static and void?",
			"answer": " You can access public declared variables anywhere in the application.\nStatic declared variables are globally accessible without creating an instance of the class.\nVoid is a type modifier that specifies that the method doesn't return any value",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are constructors in C#?",
			"answer": " A constructor is a member function in the class and has the same name as its class. Whenever the object class is created, the constructor is automatically invoked. It constructs the value of data members while initializing the class.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the different types of constructors in C#?",
			"answer": " Basically, there are five types of constructors:\nStatic constructor\nPrivate constructor\nCopy constructor\nDefault constructor\nParameterized constructor",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is static constructor?",
			"answer": "Static constructor is used to initialize static data members as soon as the class is referenced first time. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is method overloading in C#? ",
			"answer": "Method overloading is mechanism to create multiple methods with the same name and unique signature in the same class. When you go for compilation, the compiler uses overload resolution to determine the specific method to be invoked. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " Is overriding of a function possible in the same class?",
			"answer": " no",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is array? ",
			"answer": " Array is a set of related instances either value or reference types.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is ArrayList?",
			"answer": " ArrayList is a dynamic array. You can add and remove the elements from an ArrayList at runtime. In the ArrayList, elements are not automatically sorted.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is a collection? ",
			"answer": " A collection works as a container for instances of other classes. All classes implement ICollection interface.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is an interface?",
			"answer": " Interface is an abstract class that has only public abstract method. These methods only have declaration not the definition. These abstract methods must be implemented in the inherited classes.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the lock statement in C#?",
			"answer": " Lock statement is used to ensure that one thread doesn?t enter a critical section of code while another thread is in the critical section. If another thread attempts to enter a locked code it will wait, block, until the object is released.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is serialization?",
			"answer": " If you want to transport an object through network then you have to convert the object into a stream of bytes. The process of converting an object into a stream of bytes is called serialization.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between early binding and late binding in C#?",
			"answer": " Early binding and late binding are the concept of polymorphism. There are two types of polymorphism in C#.\nCompile Time Polymorphism \nIt is also known as early binding.\nRun Time Polymorphism: It is also known as late binding or method overriding or dynamic polymorphism.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " Which are the access modifiers available in C#?",
			"answer": "Following are the access modifiers generally used for accessibility:\nPublic: If you define an attribute or method as public, it can be accessed from any code of the project.\nPrivate: A private defined attribute or method can be accessed by any code within the containing class only.Protected: If you define the method or attribute as protected it can be accessed by any method in the inherited classes and any method within the same class.\nInternal: If you define an attribute or a method as internal, it is restricted to classes within the current position assembly.Protected internal: If you define an attribute or method as protected internal, access is restricted to classes within the current project assembly or types derived from the containing class. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between abstract class and interface in C#?",
			"answer": " Abstract class can have abstract and concrete methods whereas interface has only abstract methods.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between dispose() and finalize() methods in C#? ",
			"answer": " The dispose() method is explicitly called by user to free unmanaged resources such as files, database connections etc whereas finalize method is implicitly called by garbage collector to free unmanaged resources like files, database connections etc.\nThe dispose() method belongs to IDisposable interface whereas finalize() method belongs the Object class.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between method overloading and method overriding in C#?",
			"answer": " Method parameters must be different in method overloading whereas it must be same in method overriding.\nInheritance is not required in method overloading, it occurs within the same class. But inheritance is required in method overriding.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is object pool in .Net?",
			"answer": "Object pool is a container of ready to use objects. It reduces the overhead of creating new object. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is delegate in C#? ",
			"answer": "A delegate in C# is an object that holds the reference to a method. It is like function pointer in C++. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is Hashtable?",
			"answer": " A Hashtable is a collection of key/value pairs. It contains values based on the key.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is Reflection?",
			"answer": " Reflection allows us to get metadata and assemblies of an object at runtime.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is Garbage Collection?",
			"answer": "Garbage Collection is a process of releasing memory automatically occupied by objects which are no longer accessible. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "cSharp"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is MySQL? ",
			"answer": " MySQL is a multithreaded, multi-user SQL database management system which has more than 11 million installations. This is the world's second most popular and widely used open source database.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " In which language MySQL is written?",
			"answer": " MySQL is written in C and C++ and its SQL parser is written in yacc.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the technical specification of MySQL?",
			"answer": " MySQL has the following technical specifications\n\tFlexible structure\n\tHigh performance\n\tManageable and easy to use\n\tReplication and high availability\n\tSecurity and storage management ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "How many Triggers are possible in MySQL? ",
			"answer": " There are only six Triggers allowed to use in MySQL database.\n\tBefore Insert\n\tAfter Insert\n\tBefore Update\n\tAfter Update\n\tBefore Delete\n\tAfter Delete",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is heap table? ",
			"answer": " Tables that are present in memory is known as HEAP tables. When you create a heap table in MySQL, you should need to specify the TYPE as HEAP. These tables are commonly known as memory tables. They are used for high speed storage on temporary basis. They do not allow BLOB or TEXT fields.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is BLOB and TEXT in MySQL?",
			"answer": " BLOB is an acronym stands for binary large object. It is used to hold a variable amount of data.\n\tThere are four types of BLOB.\n\tTINYBLOB\n\tBLOB\n\tMEDIUMBLOB\n\tLONGBLOB\nThe differences among all these are the maximum length of values they can hold.TEXT is case-insensitive BLOB. TEXT values are non-binary strings (character string). They have a character set and values are stored and compared based on the collation of the character set.\n\tThere are four types of TEXT.\n\tTINYTEXT \n\tTEXT\n\tMEDIUMTEXT                   LONGTEXT",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is a trigger in MySQL? ",
			"answer": "A trigger is a set of codes that executes in response to some events ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between FLOAT and DOUBLE? ",
			"answer": "FLOAT stores floating point numbers with accuracy up to 8 places and allocates 4 bytes, on the other hand DOUBLE stores floating point numbers with accuracy up to 18 places and allocates 8 bytes. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the advantages of MySQL in comparison to Oracle?",
			"answer": " MySQL is a free, fast, reliable, open source relational database while Oracle is expensive, although they have provided Oracle free edition to attract MySQL users.\n\tMySQL uses only just under 1 MB of RAM on your laptop while Oracle 9i installation uses 128 MB.\n\tMySQL is great for database enabled websites while Oracle is made for enterprises.\n\tMySQL is portable.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "What are the disadvantages of MySQL? ",
			"answer": " MySQL is not so efficient for large scale databases.\n\tIt does not support COMMIT and STORED PROCEDURES functions version less than 5.0.\n\tTransactions are not handled very efficiently.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between CHAR and VARCHAR?",
			"answer": " CHAR and VARCHAR are differ in storage and retrieval.\n\tCHAR column length is fixed while VARCHAR length is variable.\n\t The maximum no. of character CHAR data type can hold is 255 character while VARCHAR can hold up to 4000 character.\n\tCHAR is 50% faster than VARCHAR.\n\tCHAR uses static memory allocation while VARCHAR uses dynamic memory allocation.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "' What does ' i_am_a_dummy flag' do in MySQL?",
			"answer": " The ' i_am_a_dummy flag' enables MySQL engine to refuse any UPDATE or DELETE statement to execute if the WHERE clause is not present.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "How to get the current date in MySQL? ",
			"answer": " SELECT CURRENT_DATE()",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the security alerts while using MySQL?",
			"answer": " Install antivirus and configure the operating system's firewall.\n\tNever use the MySQL Server as the UNIX root user.\n\tChange root username and password\n\tRestrict or disable remote access.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between Unix timestamps and MySQL timestamps?",
			"answer": " Actually both Unix timestamp and MySQL timestamp are stored as 32-bit integers but MySQL timestamp is represented in readable format of YYYY-MM-DD HH:MM:SS format. ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is MySQL default port number?",
			"answer": " MySQL default port number is 3306.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is REGEXP?",
			"answer": " REGEXP is a pattern match using regular expression. Regular expression is a powerful way of specifying a pattern for a complex search.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " How to change a password for an existing user via Mysqladmin? ",
			"answer": " Mysqladmin -u root -p password  newpassword ",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " How many columns can you create for an index?",
			"answer": " You can create maximum of 16 indexed columns for a standard table.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between NOW() and CURRENT_DATE()? ",
			"answer": " NOW() command is used to show current year, month, date with hours, minutes and seconds while CURRENT_DATE() shows the current year with month and date only.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the query to display top 20 rows?",
			"answer": " SELECT * FROM table_name LIMIT 0,20;",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "Write a query to display current date and time? ",
			"answer": " SELECT NOW();\n\tIf you want to display current date only, \n\tuse -SELECT CURRENT_DATE();",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is save point in MySQL? ",
			"answer": " A defined point in any transaction is known as savepoint.\nSAVEPOINT is a statement in MySQL which is used to set a named transaction save point with a name of identifier.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is SQLyog?",
			"answer": " SQLyog program is the most popular GUI tool for admin. It is the most popular MySQL manager and admin tool. It combines the features of MySQL administrator, phpMyadmin and others MySQL front ends and MySQL GUI tools.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},
		{
			"question": " How do you backup a database in MySQl?",
			"answer": " It is easy to backing up data with phpMyAdmin. Select the database you want to backup by clicking the database name in the left hand navigation bar. Then click the export button and make sure that all tables are highlighted that you want to backup. Then specify the option you want under export and save the output.",
			"Priority": " medium",
			"language": "mySQL"
		},

		{
			"question": " What is ASP?",
			"answer": "ASP stands for Active Server Pages. It is also known as classic ASP. It is a server side technology provided by Microsoft which is used to create dynamic and user-friendly web pages. It uses different scripting languages to create dynamic web pages which can be run on any type of browsers ",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is ASP.NET?",
			"answer": "ASP.Net is a specification by Microsoft which is used to create web applications and web services. It is a part of .Net framework. You can create ASP.Net applications in most of the .Net compatible languages like Visual Basic, C# etc. ASP.Net provides much better performance than scripting languages. ",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between the ASP and ASP.NET? ",
			"answer": " The main difference between ASP and ASP.Net is that ASP is interpreted, while ASP.Net is compiled. ASP uses VBScript, therefore when the ASP page is executed, it is interpreted. On the other hand, ASP.Net uses .Net languages like C# and VB.NET, which is compiled to Microsoft intermediate language.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the advantages of ASP.NET?",
			"answer": " ASP.Net is the next generation of ASP technology platform. It is superior to ASP in the following ways: Highly Scalable\nCompiled Code \nUser Authentication\nLanguage Support\nThird party control\nConfiguration and Deployment is easy.\nObject and Page caching\nStrict coding\n requirements",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the concept of Postback in ASP.NET? ",
			"answer": " Postback is a request which is sent from a client to the server from the same page user is working with. There is HTTP POST request mechanism in ASP.NET. It basically posts a complete page back to server to refresh the whole page. ",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " How to check that the page is Post Back?",
			"answer": "The 'isPostBack' property of page object is used to check that the page is posted back or not. ",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the parent class of all web server control?",
			"answer": " System.Web.UI.Control class",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between ASP.NET Webforms and ASP.NET MVC? ",
			"answer": " ASP.NET Webforms uses the page controller approach for rendering layout. In this approach, every page has its own controller.On the other hand, ASP.NET MVC uses Front Controller approach. In this approach, there is a common controller for all pages.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between session object and application object??",
			"answer": " The session object is used to maintain the session of each user. A session id is generated if a user enters in the application and when the user leaves the application, the session id is automatically deleted.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "  How to sign out from forms authentication?",
			"answer": " FormsAuthentication.Signout() method is used to sign out from forms authentication.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " How to display validation messages in one control?",
			"answer": " By the help of ValidationSummary control, we can display all validation messages in one control.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between authentication and authorization? ",
			"answer": " Authentication is a process of identifying user whereas authorization is used to check the access rights of an identified user",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "  Which object encapsulates state or data of an user?",
			"answer": " Session object.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is ViewState?",
			"answer": "ViewState is a features of ASP.NET to store the values of a page before it is submitted to the server. After posting the page, data from is ViewState is restored ",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is ViewState information stored?",
			"answer": "It is stored in HTML hidden field. ",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What are the differences between the Response.Write() and Response.Output.Write()? ",
			"answer": " Response.Write() is used for normal output whereas Response.Output.Write() is used for formatted output.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "Define the types of configuration files. ",
			"answer": " there are two types of config : Application Level config = Web.config.\nMachine Level config = Machine.config ",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between Web config and Machine config files?",
			"answer": " Web config file is specific to web application whereas Machine config file is specific to machine or server.\n\tThere can be multiple web config files in an application but only one machine config file",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is MVC?",
			"answer": " MVC stands for Model View Controller. It is a design pattern that is used to separate business logic and presentation logic. It is used to develop highly customized application.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are the built-in objects in ASP.NET?",
			"answer": " The major built-in objects are given below:\n\tApplication\n\tSession\n\tContext\n\tRequest\n\tResponse\n\tServer\n\tTrace",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is Role-base security? ",
			"answer": " In role-based security, you can assign a role to each user. In such way, each user has privilege to do some task. ",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is cookie? ",
			"answer": " ookie is a small piece of information which is stored at client side. There are two types of cookie Session/Temporary Cookie: valid for single session\nPersistent Cookie: valid for multiple session",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the default timeout for cookie? ",
			"answer": " 30 minutes.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " Which protocol is used to call web service?",
			"answer": " HTTP protocol.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the file extension of web service? ",
			"answer": " File extension of web service is .asmx.",
			"Priority": " easy",
			"language": "dotNet"
		},

		{
			"question": " What is Data Structure? Explain.",
			"answer": " Data structure is a way that specifies how to organize and manipulate the data. It also specifies the relationship between them. It provides some algorithms to make data access more efficient and easy",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "  In which areas data structures are applied extensively?",
			"answer": " Data structures are applied extensively in the following areas of computer science:\n\tCompiler Design,\n\tOperating System,\n\tDatabase Management System,\n\tStatistical analysis package,\n\tNumerical Analysis,\n\tGraphics,\n\tArtificial Intelligence, \n\tSimulation",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between file structure and storage structure? ",
			"answer": "Difference between file structure and storage structure:\nThe main difference between file structure and storage structure is based on memory area that is being accessed.\nStorage structure: When we deal with the structure that resides in the main memory of the computer system, known as the storage structure.\nFile structure: When we deal with an auxiliary structure then it is referred as file structures ",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " Which data structures are used with the following areas: RDBMS, Network data model and hierarchical data model?",
			"answer": " RDBMS uses Array data structure\n\tNetwork data model uses Graph\n\tHierarchal data model uses Trees",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " What are Binary trees?",
			"answer": " A Binary Tree is a type of data structure that has two nodes: A left node and a right node. In programming, binary trees are actually an extension of the linked list structures.",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is a Stack?",
			"answer": " A stack is a data structure in which only the top element can be accessed. As data is stored in the stack, each data is pushed downward, leaving the most recently added data on top.",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is a multidimensional array? ",
			"answer": " A multidimensional array stores data in multiple indexes. It is used when the storing data that cannot be represented using a single dimensional indexing, such as data representation in a board game, tables with data stored in more than one column.",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is a linked list in data structure?",
			"answer": " A linked list is a sequence of nodes in which each node is connected to the node following it. It makes a chain like link of data storage.",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "  If you are using C language to implement the heterogeneous linked list, what pointer type should be used?",
			"answer": " The heterogeneous linked list contains different data types, so it is not possible to use ordinary pointers for this. For this work, you have to use a generic pointer type like void pointer because void pointer is capable of storing pointer to any type.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " How many minimum numbers of queues are needed to implement the priority queue?",
			"answer": " Two queues are needed. One queue is used for actual storing of data and another for storing priorities.",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "Which data structure is used to perform recursion? ",
			"answer": " Stack is used to perform recursion because of its LIFO (Last In First Out) property. It knows whom to return when the function has to return.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " When should you use binary search engine?",
			"answer": " A binary search algorithm is used to search a list when the elements are already in order or sorted. The list starts searching in the middle, if the middle value is not the target search key, it will check to see if it will continue the search on the lower half of the list or the higher half. The split and search will then continue in the same manner.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "How to reference all the elements in a one-dimension array? ",
			"answer": " It can be done by using an indexed loop such that the counter runs from 0 to the array size minus one. By this manner, you can reference all the elements in sequence by using the loop counter as the array subscript.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " Which notations are used in Evaluation of Arithmetic Expressions using prefix and postfix forms?",
			"answer": " Polish and Reverse Polish notations.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " Give some example of the application of Tree-data structure?",
			"answer": " Application of Tree- data structure:\n\tThe manipulation of Arithmetic expression,\n\tSymbol Table construction,\n\tSyntax analysis",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " Give the example of some applications that make use of Multilinked Structures?",
			"answer": " Sparse matrix,\n\tIndex generation",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "Are linked lists considered linear or non-linear data structures? ",
			"answer": " A linked list is considered both linear and non-linear data structure depending on the situation.\nOn the basis of data storage, it is considered as non-linear data structure.\nOn the basis of access strategy, it is considered as linear data-structure.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is the difference between NULL and VOID?",
			"answer": " Null is actually a value, whereas Void is a data type identifier. \nA null variable simply indicates an empty value, whereas void is used to identify pointers as having no initial size.",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": " What is a postfix expression?",
			"answer": " An expression which each operator follows its operand is known as postfix expression. The main benefit of this form is that there is no need to group sub-expressions in parentheses or to consider operator precedence",
			"Priority": "easy",
			"language": "ds"
		},
		{
			"question": "What is the difference between PUSH and POP? ",
			"answer": " PUSH and POP operations specify how data is stored and retrieved in a stack.\n\tPUSH: PUSH specifies that data is being  pushed  into the stack.\n\tPOP: POP specifies data retrieval, and in particular refers to the topmost data being accessed. ",
			"Priority": "medium",
			"language": "ds"
		}

	]
}
